TIMOTHY COOK

7241 Catamaran Dr. Citrus Heights, CA 95621 · 916-342-6637 t-b-cook@hotmail.com · linkedin.com/in/tim-cook-7b709356

Strategic leadership professional with 19 years of experience accelerating in multiple divisions of Walmart Stores, Inc. (Walmart, Sam's Club, and Walmart.com) seeking to use strong relationship, finance, quality control, operations, and organizational skills to continue in a senior manager role. My professional goal is to continue learning new areas of the business, while improving and causing positive change in other individuals and teams.

EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

CLUB MANAGER, SAM'S CLUB – FOLSOM, CA

- Responsible for 170 hourly associates and 5 salaried managers with over \$75 million in sales.
- Grew member base by 7.5% over previous year gaining market share over Costco.
- Moved club to a high volume category (>\$75 million) this year.
- Layered on an additional \$12 million over previous year.
- Developed load check in process to match BOL and quality resulting in over \$100,000 in quality claims LY, leading the region.
- Reduced Fresh throws through FIFO and receiving processes saving \$165,000 from plan LY.
- Established AM and PM culling process and daily follow up of quality utilizing FST technology leading to a healthier P&L and fresh traffic increase of 7.9% over LY.

SEPTEMBER 2015 – SEPTEMBER 2018

COMPLEX STORE MANAGER, WALMART – SACRAMENTO, CA

- Responsible for 4 salaried managers and 90 hourly associates.
- Largest sales increase in format at 35% in 2018.
- Highest EBT penetration in region lead to largest sales in the first 10 days of the month for the market, resulting in key planning for merchandising and staffing.
- Highest traffic count in Northern, CA with 25,000 transactions a week with smallest square footage.
- Engagement score of 81% highest in the market in 2017.
- Lowest turnover rate in the market at 59%.
- Created a talent pool for market, promoting my Assistant Manager to Store Manager and three department managers to Assistant Managers.
- Reduced store's out of stocks from 2,000 to 500 through active 4x4 tours and routines built around process follow-up.

FEBRUARY 2014 – SEPTEMBER 2015
CLUB MANAGER, SAM'S CLUB – SACRAMENTO, CA

- Responsible for 6 salaried managers and 160 hourly associates with \$70 million in annual sales.
- Strengthened the P&L health by saving \$275,000 in SG&A expenses over previous year with a 98% index to plan.
- Profit increase over previous year by 118% with the club turning a profit for the first time in several years.
- Accelerated engagement scores, improving each year with a score of 69% to 88%.

FEBRUARY 2012 - JANUARY 2014

CLUB MANAGER, SAM'S CLUB - COCOA, FL

- Responsible for 6 Salaried Managers and 160 Hourly associates with \$65 million in annual volume.
- Increased member base by 7% in a declining market through strong membership and fresh performance.
- Increased fresh traffic by 12% over previous year.
- Highest base growth increase in the region all club associates were awarded a base growth incentive.
- Achieved 103% to sales plan and 105% to profit plan.
- Market Club of the Year 2014.

AUGUST 2010 – JANUARY 2012

WALMART'S FIRST EVER – MULTICHANNEL MANAGER, WALMART.COM – SAN BRUNO/SAN JOSE, CA

- Responsible for launching and implementing Walmart's first delivery service program in San Jose, CA.
- Engineered training and implementation for future stores' launch across US by gathering learnings from ASDA (Donnington Wood Store) during UK visit.
- Established relationships with Porterville Walmart DC manager Kent Delperdang to understand logistics.
- Successfully launched into Walmart curbside pickup nationwide.

JULY 2009 – SEPTEMBER 2010

CO-MANAGER/SHIFT MANAGER, WALMART – SACRAMENTO, CA

- Responsible for 8 salaried managers and 450 hourly associates with \$115 million in annual sales.
- Worked directly under store manager and operated all grocery/consumables and fresh business.
- Selected by the regional team to assist the opening of San Jose, CA Supercenter. Utilized fresh experience to teach, train and develop the team to Grand Open effectively and operate all fresh operations going forward.

FEBRUARY 2004-JUNE 2009

ASSISTANT MANAGER, WALMART – ORANGEVALE, CA / JACKSONVILLE, FL / LAND O' LAKES, FL

- Opened new prototype Supercenter as fresh assistant manager (Orangevale, CA).
- Assigned to assist remodel of Kendall, FL Supercenter.
- Assisted Walmart Neighborhood Market launch in Tampa, FL to teach and train associates on fresh operations and inventory.

EDUCATION

JANUARY 2002

PASCO-HERNANDO STATE COLLEGE (DEGREE NOT COMPLETE)

18 credits completed

JANUARY 2002

PASCO-HERNANDO STATE COLLEGE (DEGREE NOT COMPLETE)

12 credits completed

SKILLS

- Fresh/Food operations
- New Store/club openings

- People development
- Community involvement
- Relationship networking

ACTIVITIES AND AWARDS

- •
- Previous Board of Director for Cocoa Beach Regional Chamber of Commerce.
- Previous Board of Reference Member for Brevard Public Schools.
- Previous member of the Cocoa, Rotary Club.
- WAGJLL Board Member with Walmart Neighborhood Markets.
- Market Club of the Year 2014
- Selected for Dacona Smith's Club Manager Counsel in 2019.
- Highest AES scores in 2017